AVNEET KAUR

India



avneet2687@yahoo.com



+91-9988490887



linkedin.com/in/major-avneet-kaur-1b3b84125

Summary

A Military veteran with total of 12+ years of experience in Cybersecurity Governance, risk and compliance along with Cybersecurity project management. Experienced in understanding and implementation of ISO 27001 standards, ITILV4 framework, NIST, GDPR, COBIT, COMPTIA Security fundamentals along with PRINCE2 project management skills. Managed a project of application penetration testing services for a value of 5,43,000 USD as a PMO.

Experience



Manager

EY

Aug 2021 - Present (1 year 7 months)

- * As a PMO for a penetration testing services for an EMEIA client, managed a team of 10+ penetration testers for successful delivery of the quality client requirements in time.
- * Led the project from initiation through implementation and establishing the clear project requirements.
- * Prepared the SOW for the clear understanding of the scope of work from client and deadlines for the deliverables
- *Facilitated and led the daily stand-up calls with the team members to ensure the quality of the deliverables as well as meeting the deadlines.
- * Led the weekly status reporting calls with the client to provide regular feedback on the work program and deliverables.
- * Conceptualized and prepared the complete project documentation, SOPs for easy reference and knowledge transfer to any newly onboarded resource.
- *Monitored the progress and performance of the project schedule by maintaining various trackers to keep the project on track and deliver the client deliverables in time.
- *Drove the Best Practices and lessons learnt, by documenting and ensuring the same is followed to avoid any client escalations.
- *Conceptualized the skill matrix and resource availability to avoid any delays for client deliverables.
- * Smooth execution and quality deliverables helped in driving more business from client wherein apart from application testing, configuration review was also included in the revised SOW.
- * Appreciated with SPOT Award for the project management skills and smooth execution of the project by EY.
- * Got promoted to Manager from a senior consultant within a year being customer focused, developing business and delivering quality work.



EY

Feb 2021 - Apr 2021 (3 months)

- * Built the understanding of Cybersecurity and its domains.
- * Learnt the working culture and environment of a technology consulting organization.

- * Learnt about basics of IAM, Data privacy and protection, Governance risk and compliance, Threat and exposure management, Vulnerability management.
- * Hands on training on Qualys vulnerability management tool.
- *Understanding and documenting client technology processes and requirement, performing root cause analysis.
- *Monitoring progress, managing risks and ensuring key stake holders are always informed about the progress and outcomes



Associate Project Manager

JPMorgan Chase & Co.

Apr 2021 - Jul 2021 (4 months)

Assisting in establishing a Project Management Office to oversee multiple projects.

Liaising with stakeholders such as project personnel, vendors, and end-users regarding project requirements.

Outlining, defining, and initiating the project.

Implementing document control policies and documentation templates.

Maintaining a good working knowledge of assigned component projects.

Evaluating standards of component products.

Monitoring project progress and implementing changes where necessary.

Monitoring expenditures in accordance with the budget.

Ensuring compliance with objectives, organizational policies, procedures, and standards.

Compiling project reports and informing management regarding problems.

Ensuring project complies with best practices, SOPs, PMO policies, and other policies.



🔀 Senior Project Manager

Indian Army

Oct 2009 - Sep 2020 (11 years)

- *Procurement of IT Equipment worth 65000 USD by determining and recommending best suited to Organizational needs.
- *Planned, evaluated and implemented the improved IR sensor Security projects of Military cantonment worth 50,000 USD by optimal utilization of the resources and skill set.
- *Conceptualized & developed a master data for almost 3000 different army equipment to identify & design strategic transformation plans and implementing a target operating model that leveraged new business enablement based on the analysis of data available, reducing costs to 30% and streamlining operations by implementing new computer software and hardware.
- *Managed Employee data of more than 700 employees (PII, PHI, Name, ID, personal details, service, trade, skill, hourly rate, leave, retirement.)
- *Successfully led and managed Procurement, distribution, Stores, Spares, Material, Equipment and Logistics Planning.
- *Managed master data Confidentiality, integrity, availability, acted as a custodian of the Information Security Program, and provided periodic updates to the relevant management levels.
- *Performed internal audit procedures, including identifying and defining issues, developing criteria, reviewing and analyzing evidence, and documenting processes and procedures.
- *Conducted security audits of Army facilities and equipment to identify potential weaknesses in security measures.
- *Conducted surveillance of building entrances and exits to detect potential threats to security or safety of the organization and its assets.

- *Maintaining records of security activities and incidents, including maintenance of computerized databases for info breach.
- *Organized security awareness training and conducted internal audits to curb cyber security violations and documented the audits quarterly with mitigation measures.
- *Directed investigations, facilitated report generation and coordinated legal course of action including finalization of legal documentation for reported incidents of breach.

Education

Indian Institute of Management, Lucknow

General business Management, Business Administration and Management, General

- Pondicherry University
 MBA, HR
- Punjab Technical University
 B. TECH, ECE
- Central Board of Secondary Education
 Higher Secondary Education

Licenses & Certifications

- Control Objectives for Information and Related Technology ISACA
- Cybersecurity
- Certified network security specialist ICSI (International CyberSecurity Institute), UK
- Microsoft certified azure fundamentals Microsoft
- # Foundation of Data Governance Learning Path Collibra
- certified ScrumMaster (CSM) Scrum Alliance
- ot GRC Professional OneTrust
- ISO 27001 Lead Auditor Information Security Certification The Knowledge Academy

- OAMELOS IT Information Library Foundations Certification (ITIL) AXELOS Global Best **Practice**
- OAMELOS PRINCE2 Agile® Foundation & Practitioner AXELOS Global Best Practice
- Vulnerability Management Qualys

Skills

Project Delivery • Problem Solving • Team Management • Cybersecurity • Project Management • Project Planning • Customer Relationship Management (CRM) • Team Building • Management • Microsoft Office

Honors & Awards



SPOT - EY

Apr 2022

It gives me immense pride to recognize your dedication and perseverance that contributed to our success. The efforts you put in are truly commendable and it has meaningfully contributed in creating an exceptional experience at EY GDS. Your passion, dedication and hard work always amaze us! Thank you for everything you do. May you continue the same every single day for the rest of your career.

Kudos!



Living EY Values - EY

Nov 2022

This appreciation follows you for the effort put in to train college students to make them industry ready through "Training sessions with ICT Academy FY22" Ripples program. Industry expert sessions to give a hands-on demonstration on technology topics. SharePoint training to women to make them industry ready. Together we create better lives.



International Project Management - EY

Dec 2022

It gives me immense pride to recognize your dedication and perseverance that contributed to our success. The efforts you put in are truly commendable and it has meaningfully contributed in creating an exceptional experience at EY GDS. Your passion, dedication and hard work always amaze us! Thank you for everything you do. May you continue the same every single day for the rest of your career.

Kudos!